人人影視傾情奉獻
翻譯  草草
翻譯  杏仁斯嘉麗
翻譯  小飯
翻譯  江湖人稱王姑娘
翻譯  丶Charl
時間軸  壬虛浪影
顧問  老杜
后期  餓得慌
校對  草草
總監  草草
紙牌屋
第四季  第五集
兩個月前  盧卡斯·古德溫被從印第安納州
Lucas Goodwin was released from a federal detention center
盧卡斯·古德溫的家
泰瑞豪特一家聯邦監獄釋放
in Terre Haute, Indiana, two months ago.
聯調局調查員搜查了他在俄亥俄州代頓的
FBI investigators searched his witness protection residence
-證人保護計劃住處  -他怎么會被釋放
- in Dayton, Ohio... - Why was he even out of jail?
他在一起調查中協助了司法部
He helped the DOJ with an ongoing investigation.
你怎么會不知道
How did you not know that?
證人保護計劃  出于安全考慮高度保密
WITSEC. Only need-to-know for security reasons.
我們今天在他家發現了這個
We found this today at his house.
大概是遺書吧
A suicide note, I guess.
外遇
佐伊·巴恩斯
這不能被公開
This can't go public.
我們還沒對媒體透露半句
We haven't told the press anything.
但這是證據
But this is evidence.
一旦報告出來
Once the report comes out...
道格·斯坦普
幕僚長
瑞秋·波斯納
把這個電郵給我
Email this to me.
安德伍德夫人
Mrs. Underwood?
現在凌晨兩點了  您要回家嗎
It's two o'clock in the morning. Would you like to go home?
嗯  我待會兒就出去
Oh, yes, I'll be out in a moment.
是  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
他的肝再生速度不夠快
His liver is just not regenerating fast enough.
那具體是什么意思
What does that mean, exactly?
他需要移植  否則會死
He needs a transplant, or he'll die.
-什么時候  -幾天之內
- How soon? - Days.
待移植者瀕臨死亡
我們將他列為了1號情況
We've made him Status 1.
我們應該能為他找到合適的肝臟
I'm optimistic we'll find him a suitable liver.
接受者名單是機密
The recipient list is classified.
只有您二位政府成員知情
You're the only two members of the administration who've been briefed.
第一夫人知道了嗎
Is the First Lady aware?
是的  我今天下午告訴她了
Yes, I informed her this afternoon.
我可以進來嗎
May I?
請吧
Please.
我知道很晚了  但他們說你沒睡
I know it's late, but they said you were up, so...
我知道  我就是一天都沒吃東西了
No, I know. I just hadn't eaten all day.
你也是吧
I'm sure you haven't.
-來點沙拉嗎  -好啊  謝謝
- Would you like some salad? - Sure. Thank you.
弗蘭克的事  真是可怕
It's scary, about Frank.
弗蘭西斯是個斗士
Well, Francis is a fighter.
真希望我能問他的建議
I wish I could ask his advice.
我明早要跟佩特羅夫通電話了
I have my call with Petrov in the morning.
我對計劃頗為了解  這點我有自信
I feel good about my understanding of the plan.
我擔心的是他在電話里威脅我
My concern is him railroading me on the call.
你希望我跟你一起打嗎
Well, would you like me to be on it?
多個人聽聽
An extra set of ears.
我不知道凱茜會有什么想法
I don't... I don't know how Cathy would feel about that.
不非得讓她知道啊
Well, she doesn't need to know.
我可以在這里聽
I could just listen from up here.
如果你有麻煩  或許我可以發點建議過去
And maybe I could type a note if you get into trouble.
...對總統的恢復閉口不談
...tight-lipped on the president's recovery.
到目前  據報他情況穩定
As of now, he's reported to be in stable condition.
尚無媒體被允許進入醫院
No press has been allowed into the hospital.
共和黨候選人威爾·康威
Republican presidential hopeful Will Conway
今早在亞利桑那州一場集會上提到了總統
spoke of the president at a rally in Arizona this morning.
我經常批評安德伍德總統
I've criticized President Underwood often.
但此刻  他是我們的總統
But right now, he's our president...
明天來吧  我們沒油了
Come back tomorrow. We're all out.
兩黨要團結一致
...and we have to pull together, both sides of the aisle...
我們今天沒油了
We're all out for today.
抱歉  明天再來吧
Sorry, come back tomorrow.
-沒油了  沒油了  -不是吧
- We're all out, guys. We're all out. - Are you serious?
明天再來吧  我們今天沒油了  先生
Come back tomorrow. We're all out for today, sir.
真扯
Bullshit!
我能從你這兒吸幾加侖嗎
Can I siphon a couple of gallons from you?
五十塊  我已經沒油了
Fifty bucks. I'm running on fumes.
我還得送孩子上學  送老公上班
I gotta get my kids to school, and my husband to work--
八十塊  兩加侖
Eighty bucks, two gallons.
抱歉  幫不了你  抱歉
Sorry, I can't help you. Sorry.
普通汽油
現金支付
高級汽油
精品汽油
現金支付
杰·夏普
你在華府嗎
這邊加班加點呢
總統  油價危機
如果能休息一下就太好了
雷·丹頓
佛羅里達呢  看爸媽來了
杰·夏普
或許也好
誘惑最討厭了
雷·丹頓
我想你
接通了嗎
The line's open?
莫斯科就等您了  先生
Moscow is ready when you are, sir.
放在這里就好
You can set it up here.
我的小抄
My Cliff Notes.
我準備好了
I'm ready.
說話別含糊其辭
自信  你有籌碼的
總統先生  您已與佩特羅夫總統接通
Mr. President, you're on with President Petrov.
總統先生
Mr. President.
俄羅斯舉國上下都在為總統的康復祈禱
All of Russia is praying for the president's recovery.
請代我轉達對安德伍德夫人的問候
I hope you will extend my warm thoughts to Mrs. Underwood.
我會的
I certainly will.
你真是勇敢
You're a brave man
在如此艱難的時刻接手
to take over during such difficult times.
我只想確保
I just want to make sure
我們找到可行方案解決這場油價...
we find a manageable resolution to this oil--
我讀過你寫的一些書  總統先生
I've read some of your books, Mr. President.
我剛讀完《學會學習》
I just finished Learning to Learn.
很不錯
It was good.
謝謝
Thank you.
有一章關于想象的令我很感興趣
There was a chapter on visualization that really interested me.
是的  是學生可用的工具  幫助他們
Yes, it's a... A tool for students. It helps them--
我想請你想象一下
I would like you to visualize something.
你站在苔原上
Now, you're standing in the tundra.
大風  暴雪
Um, wind, snow...
機器在鉆透冰層
machines drilling through the ice,
長長的管線延伸至遠處的地平線  你能想象嗎
long pipelines stretching to the horizon. Do you see?
如果你想談西伯利亞  我很樂意...
If you want to talk about Siberia, I'm more than happy to--
不不  你不是在想象
No, no, no. You're not visualizing,
副總統先生
Mr. Vice President.
閉上你的眼睛
Close your eyes.
說話別含糊其辭
自信  你有籌碼的
配合他  讓他說
好吧  閉上了
All right. They're closed.
很好  那么
Good. Now...
想象工人
picture the men
在鉆井和管線上工作
working those drills and pipelines.
他們什么樣
What do they look like?
大棉衣  戴手套  穿著靴子
Um, heavy coats, gloves, boots.
他們是
Are they...
中國人嗎
Chinese?
瞧  當我想象的時候
You see, when I picture this,
我看不到中國人
I don't see Chinese.
我同意  中國的控制權越少越好
I agree with you. The less control the Chinese have, the better.
那你為什么把米爾金送去中國
Then why did you send Milkin to China?
你不肯跟我們談判
You weren't negotiating with us.
我們覺得或許他們的運氣會更好
We thought they might have more luck.
他們的要求會讓我們陷入比之前更糟的境地
Their demands would leave us worse off than we were before.
我可以讓國際貨幣基金組織拿出一半的救市資金
I can get the IMF to provide half the bailout.
這可以制衡中國對開采權的要求
This would counteract the Chinese demands for drilling rights--
你是想挑撥我們
You are playing us off each other.
總統先生
Mr. President--
我覺得  你是自不量力了  布萊斯先生
I think you're in over your head, Mr. Blythe.
容我解釋一下
If you would just give me a chance to elaborate--
憑什么讓你解釋
Why give you a chance?
你對俄羅斯  對中國有什么了解
What do you know about Russia? About China?
我已經聽過了...
I've been briefed on--
抱歉  但是
Forgive me, but, uh...
我不愿跟
I don't feel comfortable
總統以外的人進行談判
negotiating with anyone other than the president.
等他康復  或許我們可以談談
When he recovers, perhaps he and I can speak.
說話別含糊其辭
自信  你有籌碼的
配合他  讓他說
告訴他總統可能會死
我們完事了嗎
So, are we finished?
說話別含糊其辭
自信  你有籌碼的
配合他  讓他說
告訴他總統可能會死
總統情況很糟
The president's in very bad shape.
先生
Sir...
多嚴重
How serious is it?
說話別含糊其辭
自信  你有籌碼的
配合他  讓他說
告訴他總統可能會死
他得習慣跟你商議
他需要肝臟移植
He needs a liver transplant.
我不知道
I wasn't aware that...
你最好習慣跟我磋商
You better get used to negotiating with me.
如果總統死了  那就是你和我
If the president dies, it's you and I...
否則沒得可談
or nothing at all.
抱歉  總統先生
My apologies, Mr. President.
我無意侮辱你
I didn't intend to insult you.
我們繼續協商  我只求這個
Let's keep a dialogue open. That's all I'm asking.
我想給你一份應對中方要求的
I'd like the opportunity to present you with a detailed proposal
具體提議
countering the Chinese demands.
我會讓國務卿杜蘭特跟你的外交部長接洽
I'll have Secretary Durant work with your foreign minister,
然后我們再談
and then we'll take it from there.
這樣可以嗎
Are you open to that?
當然
Of course.
我很期待看到你的提議
I look forward to reviewing your proposal.
謝謝  總統先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
先生  這消息我們還不希望透露出去
Sir, we didn't want that to get out to the press yet.
美國人民反正也該知道
The American people deserve to know, anyway.
先生  俄羅斯人是見軟就欺
Sir, the Russians don't respond well to weakness.
現在他們知道總統...
Now that they know that the president--
你聽到他說愿意協商了
You heard him say he's open to negotiation.
我認為這是進展
I'd say that's progress.
四天了  還沒有嗎
Four days and still nothing?
沒有記者招待會  沒有通報
No press conference, no briefing.
我們得讓他們
We have to let them conduct
按自己的步調進行調查
their investigation on their own terms.
感覺好像我們被蒙在鼓里
Feels like we're being shut out.
不僅僅是聯調局
This isn't just the bureau.
他們還得跟國土安全部協調
They have to coordinate with Homeland
-確保敏感...  -扯淡
- and make sure nothing sensitive-- - That's bullshit.
古德溫有什么情況你不希望我們知道
There's something about Goodwin that you don't want us to know.
不對
Wrong.
我跟你一樣想知道他這么做的動機
I wanna know why he did this just as much as you do...
但我們得讓聯調局做他們的工作
But we've gotta let the FBI do its job.
跟我去看他時是同一個論調
Same theory as when I visited him.
那是他達成認罪協議之前  是嗎
And that was before he struck the plea, correct?
我鼓勵他認罪的
I encouraged him to plead guilty.
他的宣稱毫無依據
His claims were unsubstantiated.
跟我們說說你去見古德溫之前
Tell us about your meeting with the president
跟總統的見面
prior to that meeting with Goodwin.
盧卡斯拜托我調查  我就調查了
Lucas asked me to investigate. I did.
因此采訪了安德伍德
That involved an interview with Underwood.
你還留著筆記嗎
You still have your notes?
沒有搜查令我不會交出筆記
No notes without a warrant.
媒體  沒日沒夜地打
The press. Calling non-stop.
我們建議調查期間你不要跟任何人...
We suggest you don't speak to anyone while we're still--
別擔心  我完全不想被扯進來
Don't worry. I don't have any interest in getting dragged into this.
我去把筆記找出來
Let me go dig up those notes.
布萊斯  他告訴佩特羅夫總統需要移植
Blythe... He told Petrov the president needs a transplant.
他為什么要那么做
Why would he do that?
佩特羅夫把他氣到了
Petrov got under his skin.
這就是為什么我們本該按你丈夫的計劃來
This is why we should've carried out your husband's plan.
我們給了莫斯科太多操作的空間
We're giving Moscow too much room to maneuver--
我們別談論無法改變的事了  道格
Let's not debate what we can't change, Doug.
如果莫斯科知道了  我們就得通知媒體
If Moscow knows, we'll have to notify the press.
我們明天就說
We're doing that tomorrow.
由薩克遜醫生來做通告
Dr. Saxon will do the briefing.
不  我來吧
No, I'll do it.
還是由第一夫人來說的好
It's better coming from the First Lady.
我同意
I agree.
這事我們也得應對一下
We need to address this, too.
聯調局在古德溫家找到了他的遺書
The FBI found Goodwin's notes in his house.
可以給處理掉嗎
Can we make them disappear?
不行  已經被收為證據了
No, it's already been catalogued.
我們得先一步采取行動控制輿論
We need to get out ahead of it and control the story.
好吧  給我弄一份目前為止的調查報告
All right. Get me a copy and report on the investigation so far.
我想見他
I wanna see him.
總統
The president.
特勤局不許我進去
The Secret Service still won't let me.
請允許斯坦普先生見我丈夫
I'd like Mr. Stamper to have access to my husband, please.
我們有嚴格命令  夫人  只有您
We have strict orders, ma'am. Only you and--
需要我親自打給副總統嗎
Would you like me to call the vice president myself?
道格拉斯  這位年輕人會送你進去
Douglas, this young man will escort you to his room.
謝謝
Thank you.
-幾點了  -7點剛過
- What time is it? - It's a little past 7:00.
先生  先生  是道格
Sir? Sir, it's Doug.
雖然他睜開了眼
Just because his eyes are open
但不代表他的意識完全清醒了
doesn't mean he's fully conscious.
肝功能不足
Insufficient liver function.
他的大腦泡在一堆未處理的氨中
His brain is swimming in a pool of unprocessed ammonia.
如果他能看到什么  大概也是嚴重的幻覺
If he's seeing anything, it's probably severe hallucinations.
他多久能得到肝臟
How long until he has a liver?
可能得要幾小時  可能要幾天
Could be hours. Could be days.
他是名單上第三位
He's number three on the list.
第三名
Number three?
名單按需排序
It's prioritized in terms of need
他是1號情況的第一位
and who was listed first as a Status 1.
他是美國總統啊
He's the President of the United States.
這是法律
It's the law.
納·格林
我們知道是誰泄露了照片
賽斯·格雷森
道·斯坦普
我上車打給你
司法部長要辭職
The attorney general is resigning.
把這條加入今天下午的新聞發布稿中
Add that to the press release for this afternoon.
-是她的決定還是副總統的  -我的決定
- Uh, her decision or the vice president's? - My decision.
古德溫的證人保護計劃是司法部的責任
Goodwin's WITSEC was a DOJ responsibility.
我們得找人背鍋
We needed a head to roll.
先是她
First hers...
然后你
then yours.
你明天辭職
You'll resign tomorrow.
道格  我知道你現在壓力很大  但是
Doug, I know you're under a lot of pressure, but--
是你發了那張南軍士兵照片
You sent the photo of the rebel soldier.
不是的
That's not true.
私人手機  沒在這里發
Personal phone, off the premises.
可能是有人黑了我的賬戶什么的
You know, maybe somebody hacked my account or something--
你真要再這么對我撒謊嗎
Are you really gonna keep lying to me?
我可以叫人逮捕你
I could have you arrested.
但我寧可你低調離去
But I'd rather you go quietly.
我知道些事  道格
I know things, Doug.
你證明不了什么
Nothing you can prove.
再威脅我啊
Now, threaten me again.
中國如果不加入  提議就沒戲
There's no proposal without China's involvement.
凱茜試了
Now, Cathy's tried,
但她跟他們的關系不是特別好
but she doesn't have the best relationship with them.
或許她需要幫助
Maybe she needs some help.
幫助  怎么說
Help? How?
你介意我抽煙嗎
Do you mind if I smoke?
當然不
Of course not.
我十年前戒了
I quit about ten years ago.
瑪喬莉逼我的
Marjory forced me to.
還是那么好聞
Ah, still smells delicious.
瑪喬莉死時什么樣
What was it like when Marjory died?
那是...
Oh, well, it was, um...
抱歉  如果你不愿意我們不用談這個
I'm sorry. We don't have to talk about it if you don't want.
不  沒事
No, it's fine.
我們當時已經數月沒有真正聊過了
We hadn't had a real conversation in... in months.
她的神智已經不清楚了
Her mind was gone.
她最終死時
When she finally died,
感覺好像被砍掉根肋骨
it felt like a limb had been hacked off.
我...痛不欲生
I felt... devastated.
但也如釋重負
But I also felt relieved.
我對我母親的感覺就是這樣
That's what I feel about my mother.
我不...我都沒想起來
Oh, I hadn't-- It hadn't even occurred to me.
除了弗蘭克  你母親也病了
You have Frank and your mother.
父親去世時  我幾乎崩潰了
When my father died, it destroyed me,
但想到我母親時  我毫無感覺
but when I think about Mother, I feel nothing.
-你們不親近嗎  -不
- You two aren't close? - No.
我對弗蘭西斯也是這種感覺
And I feel the same about Francis.
毫無感覺
Nothing.
我知道這聽起來很可怕
I know that must sound awful.
這很難接受
It's a lot to process.
這沒有正誤之分
There's no right way or wrong way.
-等下  慢著  -不
- Wait, hold on. - No.
瑪喬莉不會同意的
Marjory wouldn't approve.
剛剛說到哪了
We got sidetracked.
對  中國
Yes. China.
我有個主意  如果你相信我能做好的話
I have an idea, if you can trust me to handle it.
我賭上命相信你  克萊爾
I'd trust you with my goddamn life, Claire.
怎么樣
Comment c'est elle?
你不會想知道的
You don't want to know.
喝點水吧
Water?
不用  媽媽
Non, ca va, mamon.
我可不希望你們中暑了
Je veux pas vous laisse attraper un coup de chaleur, vous voyez?
我來拿  謝謝
I got it. Ah, merci.
這是誰
C'est qui?
沒誰  同事而已
Non, c'est un colleague de moi.
給你  媽媽
Mamon.
莉安
LeAnn.
找你可真難
You are a tough guy to track down.
-你來干什么  -你要趕飛機
- What are you doing here? - You have a plane to catch.
第一夫人需要你的幫助
The First Lady needs your help.
我不想和他們有任何瓜葛
I don't want to have anything to do with them.
無論你對總統的看法如何
Whatever you think of the president,
你對祖國依然負有責任
you still have a duty to your country.
就算他在我離開白宮的那天去世
Even if he dies, the day I walked out the White House,
我也向自己承諾過不會回去
I promised myself I wasn't going back.
你連我們的計劃都不知道
You don't even know what we have in mind.
無所謂  我不去
It doesn't matter. I'm not going.
我想請你離開
I'd like you to leave.
這是基本情況的材料
Here's your briefing materials.
你沒聽見我說嗎
You're not hearing me.
你真應該看一眼
You should really take a look.
她的競選會完蛋的
Her campaign would be over.
而且你父母會怎么想
And what would your parents think?
看上去就像你要利用他受傷...
It looks like you're taking advantage of the fact that he's--
康威仍在進行競選活動
Conway is still campaigning.
他是共和黨人
He's a Republican
而且他的提名已經十拿九穩
and he's already wrapped up his nomination.
和我們不一樣
Apples and oranges.
如果我們什么都不做
We are gonna lose,
陪著一個不省人事的人干坐著  會輸的
if we sit still, to a guy who's unconscious.
希瑟說得對  安德伍德在大賺同情分
Heather's right. Underwood's scoring major sympathy points.
在接下來的七個州里  他在六個州領先
He's ahead in six of the next seven states.
我們得繼續施壓
We need to keep the pressure up.
俄羅斯  油價
Russia, gas prices...
攻擊一位正與死神搏斗的總統
Attack a president who's fighting for his life?
叫你們來開會不是來辯論的
I didn't call this meeting to debate.
我要奪回那些州
I want those states back.
我們開始準備活動和媒體造勢
So let's start organizing events and media hits.
明早之前  確定初步預算和安排
Prelim budgets and schedules, by tomorrow morning.
對于古德溫的動機  人們有多種猜測
There has been much speculation as to Goodwin's motivations.
辛西婭
Cynthia.
古德溫的事進展如何
Where are we on Goodwin?
已經搞定了保安
The security guy's taken care of.
他沒看見你們在一起
He never saw the two of you together.
那其他人呢
What about others?
據他所知  沒有
None that he knows of.
但我們又不能四處詢問
But it's not like we can ask around.
在2013年11月
In November of 2013,
巴恩斯女士被華府地鐵撞擊身亡
Ms. Barnes was struck by a D.C. metrorail train.
槍手確認是盧卡斯·古德溫
華府警方將其定性為一場事故
D.C. police classified it as an accident.
有人推測...
Some have speculated that...
坐吧  雷米
Have a seat, Remy.
弗蘭克的事我很遺憾
Sorry about Frank.
拜托  省省吧
Oh, please, don't bother.
我已經聽夠了人們說他們很遺憾
I've had enough people say they're sorry,
我也知道你不是真心的
and I know you don't mean it.
我沒法按你希望的那樣幫你
I can't help you the way you want me to.
莉安告訴我她已經跟你說得很明白了
LeAnn told me she was very clear with you.
沒用的
It won't work.
塔斯克比我更不想幫你
Tusk wants to help you even less than I do.
這不是誰在幫誰  雷米
Well, nobody's doing any favors here, Remy.
他會從中獲得一大筆錢
He's going to get very rich from this.
你為什么不親自跟他說
Why don't you speak to him yourself?
因為他不會聽我的
Because he won't listen to me.
這必須聽起來像是你的主意  而不是我的
This needs to seem like your idea, not mine.
你也會撈上一大筆的
And you'll make a killing, too.
我不需要錢
I don't need the money.
因為你現在在乎的是別的
Because you care about other things now.
比如杰姬
Like Jackie.
所以你必須做成此事
Which is why you'll make this happen.
如果我當初跟鄧巴說了弗蘭克的事
If I had told Dunbar about Frank...
說他知道洗錢的事
about how he knew about the laundering,
他就當不了總統  我們現在也不會站在這兒
he wouldn't be president and we wouldn't be standing here.
但你沒有  你現在也說不了了
But you didn't and you can't now,
所以現在是這樣
so here we are.
兩小時  我們毫無進展
Two hours and we got nowhere.
他只想聽中國的反應
All he wants to hear is China.
我告訴他北京方面不回應
I told him Beijing is not responsive.
他根本不在乎
He doesn't give a damn.
第一夫人給他提過醒了
The First Lady put a bug in his ear.
不管她說了什么  他鐵了心不聽我們的了
Well, whatever bug she put in there won't crawl out.
我會安排次會面  只有你我他三人
I'll set up a meeting. Just you, me and him.
恐怕一次會面是不夠的
I don't think a meeting is enough.
我們的副總統
We have a vice president
不知道他在干什么  道格
that does not know what he is doing, Doug.
他必須把外交事務
He needs to completely turn over
全部移交給國務院
all diplomatic affairs to the State Department.
-否則我完全無能為力  -現在不行
- Otherwise, my hands are tied. - Not now.
非常緊急
This can't wait.
我們結束后  我會去找你的
When we're finished, I will come and find you.
您能讓我們單獨談談嗎  國務卿女士
Could you give us a few moments, Madam Secretary?
-賽斯  你太過分了  -沒關系
- Seth, you're out of line! - It's all right.
給我打電話
Call me.
我會的  謝謝  凱茜
I will. Thank you, Cathy.
謝謝
Thank you.
-你他媽在干什么  -你不能開除我
- What the fuck are you doing? - You can't fire me.
你不能打斷我和國務卿的會面
You don't interrupt a meeting with the Secretary of State.
我可以終結鄧巴的競選
I can end Dunbar's campaign.
今天就結束掉
We can end it today.
怎么做
How?
如果我做到  你能讓我留下嗎
If I deliver, will you keep me on?
你得先告訴我
You tell me how first.
坐吧  瑪莎
Have a seat, Martha.
我重新考慮了一下你的辭職
I've had second thoughts about your resignation.
你還想繼續當司法部長嗎
Would you like to remain as attorney general?
是的  我想
Yes, I would.
謝謝  道格
Thank you, Doug.
希瑟·鄧巴有沒有告訴過你
Did Heather Dunbar inform you
她和盧卡斯·古德溫見過面
of a meeting between herself and Lucas Goodwin?
你要讓我的下屬審問我嗎
You're having me interrogated by my own subordinates?
你能保住工作  他們才是你的屬下
They only work for you if you keep your job.
我建議你回答他們的問題
I suggest you answer their questions.
我想要我的律師在場
I'd like a lawyer present.
我提醒你  女士
Let me remind you, ma'am.
沒告知我們已經構成了隱瞞證據
Failing to have informed us constitutes withholding of evidence.
希瑟是我的朋友
Heather is a friend.
非常簡單  瑪莎
It's very simple, Martha.
跟我們合作  你就繼續當司法部長
You work with us, you stay on as AG.
不合作  我們就起訴
You don't, we prosecute.
女士們先生們  美國第一夫人
Ladies and Gentlemen, the First Lady of the United States.
大家下午好
Good afternoon, everyone.
我想向大家通報我丈夫康復的最新情況
I'd like to update you on my husband's recovery.
總統的醫療團隊
The President's medical team
昨晚做出了全面的評估
gave me a full assessment last night
他們最后的結論是
and they have come to the conclusion
總統需要肝移植
that the President is in need of a liver transplant
才能活下去
if he's to survive.
我請求全國與我共同祈禱
I'm asking the nation to pray with me
弗朗西斯能盡快等到一個健康的肝臟
that a healthy liver makes its way to Francis soon.
抱歉  請等一下
I'm sorry. A moment.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
她很厲害  對吧
She's good, isn't she?
你在這兒干什么
What're you doing here?
至于案件調查...
As for the investigation...
第一夫人需要支持
First Lady wanted some support.
...聯調局反恐處處長
...the FBI director of counterterrorism
會向大家進行全面匯報  但是...
will give you a full briefing. But...
我認為有必要親自澄清
I feel it's important to personally address
在古德溫先生住所找到的文件
the document found in Mr. Goodwin's residence
本次發布會前剛剛發到大家手上
that was made available to you just before this conference.
很多措辭足以成為引人注目的頭條新聞
It's filled with language that would make for flashy headlines,
比如謀殺  腐敗
words like "murder," "corruption."
他殺害了佐伊·巴恩斯和彼得·羅素
其中指控總統與彼得·羅素和
The accusation that the President was involved in the deaths
佐伊·巴恩斯的死有關
of Peter Russo and Zoe Barnes.
古德溫指安德伍德犯下謀殺
第一夫人發表全國講話
還有"濫用職權"這樣的字眼
Phrases like "abuse of power,"
盡管這一切沒有事實依據
while they have no basis in reality,
卻讓我們悲哀地一窺他飽受困擾的內心
they do give us a sad glimpse into a very troubled mind.
如果有人
And it pains me that anyone,
即使是有精神疾病的人
even someone who is mentally ill,
真會相信古德溫先生對我丈夫的指控
would think my husband is capable of
那會讓我十分痛心
what Mr.Goodwin believed to be true.
但最讓我心痛的是古德溫先生的父母
But mostly it pains me for Mr. Goodwin's parents,
他們還在應對失去兒子的痛苦
who are coping with the loss of their son.
據大家說  他一生中大部分時候是個好人
And, by all accounts, he was a decent man for most of his life,
但顯然  他內心的什么地方崩潰了
but clearly, something snapped in him
而他迫切需要的時候沒能得到幫助
and he never got the help he so desperately needed.
所以我懇請大家尊重他的父母
So I ask that all of you respect his parents' grief
不要對這個生病的年輕人的話加以渲染
by not sensationalizing the words of a sick young man.
讓我們記住勞倫斯和貝蒂·密查姆
And let's remember Lawrence and Betty Meechum,
他們的兒子艾德華
whose son Edward
因為古德溫先生的病獻出了自己的生命
gave his life because of Mr. Goodwin's illness.
艾德華的犧牲是我丈夫還活著的唯一原因
Edward's sacrifice is the only reason my husband is still alive.
我會永遠感激
And I'll be forever grateful
他的友誼和奉獻
for his friendship and his devoted service.
謝謝
Thank you.
反恐處處長納森·格林
Counterterrorism Director Nathan Green.
今天調查取得了新進展
Today we had a new development in the investigation.
今天下午我們詢問了司法部長
This afternoon, we interviewed the Attorney General.
她告訴了我們她和希瑟·鄧巴
She gave us a full account of a conversation she had
在槍擊當天進行的談話的全部內容
with Heather Dunbar the day of the shooting.
談話中  鄧巴女士聲稱
In this conversation, Ms. Dunbar claimed to have met
曾親自見過盧卡斯·古德溫
with Lucas Goodwin personally.
我們雖沒有理由相信
And while we have no reason to believe
鄧巴女士和刺殺企圖有任何關系
Ms. Dunbar had anything to do with the assassination attempt...
我們會就這場聲稱的談話對她進行質詢
we will be questioning her about this alleged conversation.
你們要抓她嗎
Are you arresting her?
不  女士  我們只是來問幾個問題
No, ma'am. We're here to ask a few questions.
-那你需要提出正式請求  -她現在在嗎
- Then you need to make a formal request. - Is she here now?
直接把請求發給我
Send the request directly to me,
我會和鄧巴女士的律師討論
and then I'll discuss it with Ms. Dunbar's attorneys.
凱特
Hey, Kate.
我給你打過電話  固話和手機
I tried calling. Home and cell.
座機線拔了  手機關機了
Pulled out the cord. Turned off the cell.
因為我這種人
Because of people like me.
其他人至少有禮貌沒跑來我家門口
The others had the courtesy not to show up on my doorstep.
禮貌從沒幫我達成什么目的
Courtesy never got me anywhere.
我們能談談嗎  私下談
Can we talk? Off the record.
要不是你的話...
If it were anyone but you...
幸運的是  是我
Well, luckily, it isn't.
我去牽福斯托  該遛他了
Let me get Fausto. It's time for his walk.
我是核行業的  不是化石燃料
I'm in the nuclear game, not fossil fuels.
沒人有你在中國那樣的關系
No one has the relationships you do in China.
中國人已經跟我撇清關系了
Chinese disowned me.
他們會回心轉意的
They'll come around.
誰讓你來的
Who put you up to this?
我要開自己的公司
Starting my own firm.
我以為你不干了
I thought you were out?
我那是在自欺欺人
I was fooling myself.
總統剛被槍擊
So, president gets shot,
你就忍不住要趁火打劫了
and you just can't help taking advantage of the chaos.
你所說的火  我稱之為機遇
What you call chaos, I call opportunity.
你是我的第一位客戶
And you're my first client.
祝你好運
I wish you the best.
但我不是你的第一位客戶
But I'm not your first client.
我不想跟白宮扯上關系
I don't wanna have anything to do with the White House.
你因為沃克的丑聞損失了很多錢
You lost a lot of money during the Walker scandal.
沒錯  正因此我才要拒絕你
I did, indeed, which is why I'm turning you down.
我很抱歉你跑了這么大老遠結果被拒絕
I'm sorry you came all the way out here for a "No."
你不想進監獄吧
You don't wanna go to prison, do you?
再失去僅剩的一切
Lose the rest of it?
我已經被赦免了
I've already been pardoned.
免的是洗錢罪  不是偽證罪
For the money laundering, not for perjury.
你說沃克知道  但是他不知道
You said that Walker knew, and he didn't.
你沒有說你當時在跟弗蘭克合作
What you didn't say is that you were working with Frank.
人家憑什么相信你而不是我
Why should anybody believe you more than me?
你要么賭一把
You take that chance...
然后看著克雷頓-維斯特變成低價股
and watch Clayton West become a penny stock.
要么我們成為終結石油危機的英雄
Or we're heroes for ending the oil crisis,
大家都發財  你也能重樹形象
everybody gets rich, your image is restored.
他們也許還會讓你選
They'll probably even let you choose
下一任駐北京的大使
the next ambassador in Beijing.
你并不認為那有一絲真實性
So you don't think any of it is true?
不
No.
我也想相信他
And I wanted to believe him.
那第一夫人淚眼汪汪說的那些話
So the First Lady's whole teary-eyed thing?
我覺得她是對的
I think she's right.
盧卡斯是哪里崩潰了吧
Something in Lucas snapped.
我認識的盧卡斯不會想殺死總統
I mean, the Lucas I knew wouldn't have tried to kill a president.
沒錯  我就是這意思
Exactly. That's my point.
你真覺得安德伍德殺過人嗎
You honestly think Underwood was murdering people?
你的懷疑態度哪去了
Where is your skepticism?
我懷疑盧卡斯  也懷疑白宮
I'm skeptical of Lucas and I'm skeptical of the White House.
那怎么沒證據
How come there's no proof?
一點沒有
None.
盧卡斯試了  我也試了
After Lucas tried, after I tried.
我的建議是算了吧
My advice is to let it go.
你只會重復我們的徒勞
You're gonna repeat the same goose chase we did.
我總得問一下
I had to ask.
-你的編輯怎么說  -說算了吧
- What does your editor say? - To let it go.
你看吧
You see?
-他可不如你  -那是我以前
- He's not as good as you are. - Was.
真希望你在《電訊報》工作
Wish you were at The Telegraph.
是啊  要是有人被開了就告訴我
Yeah, let me know if anyone gets fired.
活體捐獻者常見問題
門沒關
It's open.
我一收到你的短信就盡快趕過來了
I came as soon as I got your text.
發布會后我們忙得不可開交
We've been slammed since the press conference.
情況怎么樣
How's it lookin'?
鄧巴的事大受關注
Major play on the Dunbar story.
讓第一夫人去說是個好主意
It was a good idea to have the First Lady talk.
你要喝蘇打水嗎
You want a soda?
來杯水什么的嗎
A glass of water or anything?
水就好
Water's fine.
我已決定讓你留下了
I've decided you can stay.
道格  我希望你能理解
Doug, I hope you can understand.
我緊張了
I got nervous.
當時情況看起來不太好
You know, things weren't looking good and...
我想留條退路  以防萬一
yeah, I wanted an out, in case I needed one.
那的確是個錯誤  我希望我沒有那樣做
I mean, it was a mistake. I wish I hadn't.
你糾正了你的錯誤
You corrected your mistakes.
那才是最重要的  要冰塊嗎
That's all that matters. You want ice?
好的
Sure.
我們現在不能讓競選再出現問題了
We can't afford any more shake-ups in the campaign right now,
尤其總統還在醫院里
especially with the president in the hospital.
我們也不能讓你再犯錯
We also can't afford any more of your mistakes.
閉嘴  閉嘴
Shut up. Shut up!
我剛醒來的時候  說不出話
When I first woke up, I couldn't speak.
我得眨眼來表達我的反應
I had to blink my eyes if I wanted to respond.
你明白嗎
Do you understand?
如果我得不到你的忠誠
If I can't get your loyalty,
那我就要你順從
I will have your obedience.
眨眼
Blink.
Blink!
該死
Fuck!
該死的
Fucking...
給
Here.
你有病  伙計
You're fucked up, man.
-別叫了  -早上好  漢默施密特先生
- Quit it. - Good morning, Mr. Hammerschmidt.
有什么事嗎
How can I help you?
我們來還你的筆記
Uh, we're just returning your notes.
我們復印過了  這是原件
We made copies. These are the originals.
不是很有用吧
Nothing too useful, huh?
是的  先生  但還是感謝你的配合
No, sir, but thank you for your cooperation.
還有你的報紙  放在臺階上的
Your paper, too. It was on the step.
祝你今天愉快  漢默施密特先生
Well, you have a good day, Mr. Hammerschmidt.
你們也是
You, too.
不要告訴我你又餓了
Don't tell me you're hungry already.
我才喂過你  天吶
I just fed you. Good God.
來了  來了  來了  來了
I'm coming. I'm coming, I'm coming, I'm coming.
未遂刺客說法被駁斥
鄧巴未對古德溫一事做出回應
-早上好  -早上好
- Morning. - Morning.
我建議讓凱茜來做談判
I suggest we turn the negotiations over to Cathy.
如果我們一直拖著俄羅斯  油價會
If we keep stalling on Russia, gas prices will--
現在不是說這個的時候
Now is not a good time.
我不會讓總統
I won't have the president
回到一個一片混亂的白宮
come back to a White House in disarray.
我們不知道他會不會回來
We don't know that he is coming back.
他會的  我向你保證
He is. I promise you that.
你是上帝嗎  你有什么資格保證
Are you God? Who are you to say?
什么事
Yes?
塔斯克先生和丹頓先生來了
Mr. Tusk and Mr. Danton are here.
讓他們進來
Send them in.
今早安排的  我們要討論俄羅斯的事
It was arranged this morning. We're discussing Russia.
先生  我是幕僚長
Sir, I am the Chief of Staff.
這些事情你必須讓我知道
You have to keep me informed of these things.
不好意思
Excuse me,
但我覺得應該是你要聽我的
but I believe you answer to me,
而不是反過來
not the other way around.
國務卿杜蘭特應該參加這個會
Secretary Durant should be here.
這是一次私下碰面
This meeting is private.
我之后會跟你們倆討論
I'll discuss it with you both after.
總統絕不會允許雷蒙德
The president would never allow Raymond--
-總統先生  -塔斯克先生
- Mr. President. - Mr. Tusk.
雷米  很高興見到你
Remy, good to see you.
-總統先生  -斯坦普先生
- Mr. President. - Mr. Stamper.
我們稍后繼續  道格
I'll follow up with you later, Doug.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
感謝您這么快就抽出時間見我們
Thanks for taking the time to meet with us on such short notice.
石油的問題沒時間可以浪費了
Well, there's no time to waste on this oil thing.
我跟中國那邊有了些進展
I've made some progress with the Chinese.
先生  第一夫人現在在里面
Sir, the First Lady is in there right now.
她在等我
She's expecting me.
我們還想贏得選舉呢
We're trying to win an election,
你卻想提醒所有人
and you want to remind everyone
總統赦免了雷蒙德·塔斯克
that the president pardoned Raymond Tusk?
我們換個地方說
Let's find somewhere else.
這都是國家大事
These are matters of state.
你無權干涉
You don't have the authority to intervene.
如果唐納德想聽我的建議  那他就有權這么做
If Donald wants my counsel, that is his prerogative.
你故意騙我
You are deliberately deceiving me.
-你背著我  -你忘了你的身份  道格拉斯
- Going behind my-- - You have forgotten your place, Douglas.
我的身份  那你呢
My place? What about your place?
你在他最需要你時離開  還威脅他
You leave him when he needs you most, you threaten him,
現在他進了醫院  你還拆他的臺
and now that he's in here, you undermine him.
-你應該  -別說了  夠了
- You're supposed to be-- - Stop. That is enough.
我會告訴你一切
I will fill you in on everything,
但不是在這兒  而是在白宮
but not here. At the White House.
怎么了
What's happening?
他的心臟
His heart.
-醫生  -他有些偶發心律不齊
- Doctor? - He's had some sporadic arrhythmia.
-請出去一下好嗎  -好
- Will you give us the room for a moment? - Of course.
我們不能一直斗下去
We can't keep battling each other,
他都這樣子了
not with him like this.
我們需要一條新的道路
We need a new path forward,
我希望你能幫忙
and I would like your help with that.
我保證不會瞞著你
I promise I won't keep you in the dark.
等你準備好  我們白宮見
I'll meet you at the White House whenever you're ready.
我要留在這里  我覺得這更重要
I'm staying here. I think this is more important.
好
Okay.
安德伍德夫人
Mrs. Underwood.
關于如何對付俄羅斯
Mr. Tusk and Mr. Danton have a proposal
塔斯克先生和丹頓先生有個提議
about how to deal with Russia.
您今天最沒想到會見到的就是我吧
I imagine I'm the last person you expected to see today.
見到你們二位
I am a bit surprised,
我的確有些驚訝
yes, to see both of you.
大家對我們的到來肯定都有些警覺
I'm sure there's some wariness about us being here,
但我們有個對付俄羅斯的好計劃
but I think we have a good plan on how to handle Russia.
你想加入嗎
Would you like to join us?
讓雷蒙德給你詳說
Raymond can lay it out for you.
我不知道我能提供些什么
Well, I don't know what I can offer.
要是我又開始跟白宮合作的消息傳出去
Well, we're going to catch some flack if word gets out
我們肯定要受到抨擊的
that I'm back in business with the White House.
你可以幫我們平息那些聲音
You could help us smooth that over.
你的新聞發布會相當感人
Your press conference was very moving.
-弗蘭克的事  我很遺憾  -謝謝
- I'm sorry about Frank. - Thank you.
當然  他要是知道我進了總統辦公室
Of course, he'd have a conniption fit
肯定會大發脾氣
if he knew I were in the Oval Office.
他是個實用主義者  雷蒙德  只要成功就行
Well, he is a pragmatist, Raymond. Whatever works.
-我們繼續吧  -雷米
- Shall we continue? - Remy.
計劃是提出建立
So, the plan is to propose a partnership
美中能源公司合作伙伴關系
between American and Chinese energy companies.
你有點緊張
You seem nervous.
有一陣子沒見了
It's been a while.
我該怎么辦  老大
What should I do, boss?
薩克遜醫生
Dr. Saxon.
我想捐肝
I'd like to donate.
-斯坦普先生  -我是O型血
- Mr. Stamper-- - My blood type is O.
我很健康  我們開始做測試吧
I'm healthy. Let's do the tests.
健康不是捐肝的唯一標準
That's not the only criteria for donation.
你是個正在戒酒的酗酒者  我們不接受
You're a recovering alcoholic. We don't accept--
我不管什么規則
I don't care about the rules.
如果我配型成功  我希望你能做
If I'm a match, I want you to do it.
就算成功了  也幫不上忙
Even if you were, it wouldn't matter.
他已經病得太重  只有部分肝臟不夠
He's too ill for a partial liver at this point.
他需要一整個
He needs a full one.
抱歉  但我們只能等待并企盼了
I'm sorry, but we'll just have to wait and hope.
■
美國憲法規定
當總統因故不能履行職責時  應由副總統接替總統職位
但憲法最初并沒有對副總統繼位的程序作出明確規定
直到肯尼迪總統遇刺后  在冷戰的陰影下
美國國會才開始起草
并最終在1967年通過了憲法第25條修正案
對極端情況下總統權力的交接作出了詳盡規定
■
第25條修正案規定
總統被免職(彈劾)  死亡  或辭職后  由副總統接替總統職位
如果總統因故不能理政
則要向參議院臨時議長和眾議院議長提交書面聲明
副總統便立即就任成為代總統
如果副總統和內閣多數成員
或國會依法設立的其他機構的多數成員
一同向參議院臨時議長和眾議院議長提交書面聲明
稱總統無法履行其職責  則副總統可立即就任成為代總統
隨后  總統若向參議院臨時議長和眾議院議長
提交一份書面聲明  稱自己可以履行職責  便可恢復職權
如遭反對  則需國會進行進一步表決
■
在美國歷史上  出現過一次總統因病不能理政
第一夫人垂簾聽政的階段
1919年10月  美國第28任總統威爾遜因中風而臥床不起
在接下來的幾個月中  威爾遜的夫人伊迪斯為了不讓大權旁落
便將總統與外界隔絕  只允許醫生和數名助手探視
所有政務均通過第一夫人傳達給總統
許多人認為  在這個階段  真正打理國事的其實是第一夫人
后來威爾遜的健康雖有所好轉
但是直到其第二任期結束  也未完全康復
而伊迪斯對美國政務的影響  也一直持續到他們離開白宮
因此有很多人認為
伊迪斯·威爾遜實際上是美國第一位有實無名的女總統